hallelujah hallelujah I'm going to
do you love the setup okay thank you
yeah I'm going to do all of the things I
mean I cannot believe how cool this is
so hold on to your kubernetes hats
because all I had to do was add backup
enable to the harbor values. yel file
and I get a kubernetes a beautiful
kubernetes Cron job better than anything
that we had written better than anything
that I would have written uh that
already does a full postgress dump all
backup with a configurable Cron
job pause the video pause for effect if
you don't know how cool that is then you
need to like play with Harbor some more
right because you would have had to WR
write and written all this stuff so what
you're looking at right now this this is
a diff of the
resulting manifest file in our case
manifest SL uh b/a. yaml because we use
customization um and here you can see a
couple of really interesting things so
right away you see Harbor postgress oops
you see Harbor postgress SQL PG dump
ball right you also see this new label
that's on everything all the metadata is
there actually by the way I confirmed
that this is actually true because those
are those come from the charts. loock
file in the harbor chart that locks the
specific dependency on this chart which
means that when you do Helm template it
actually grabs that version of the chart
even though it's not it's not
represented in the m in the in the
values file and I'll talk about that
later that means that that actually is
the version that's being used in the
official Harbor project despite how
up sorry I swore there I was not
supposed to swear the values file is
right it's really messed up okay and so
let's keep going so I mean you can go
you can go through this on your own but
this you can see this this is like
everything you would expect there's all
the postr stuff there here is the very
very good right here is this like really
amazing PG dump ball if exists stuff
going on uh it has the password there it
actually has the volume mounts it
creates PVC separately in SL backup
which is by the way the same thing we
were naming our Mount points so it's all
the stuff that you would ever care to
have for a PG dump ball and it is built
in the official bitnami Harbor chart so
the reason it's important to say that is
because this is one less way that we are
going to divert from upstream and if you
know what it means to divert from
Upstream if you don't know what that
means let me just tell you it means work
it means work and and stress and risk
anytime that you can use a deployed
Upstream supported by the community
thing in your Enterprise you should do
it because almost always you're going to
be better now sometimes you get massive
failures like Helm itself it's a massive
failure I've been complaining and
screaming and yelling and swearing the
whole time about how screwed up the
architecture is for Helm doesn't matter
that's what people use um uh as also for
bu we're not using the operator for lots
of reasons including uh all this CDs
that are created if you don't know why
we can we can have a debate about that
but thank you for the comment um so I
every time I talk about postest I get
somebody who suggest that we use the
operator and that's a short-sighted
recommendation um that's just it's fine
it's just not not taking into account
our s our situation uh this is by the
way this is harbor not postest so it's
postgress inside Harbor okay so what
what I'm so the takeaway from this very
short video is hey look here and look
all I had to do to get that let me let
me show you the other thing so by the
way here is the chart lock while we're
there here's the chart lock that says
you are getting postest version 15.9 of
the chart which is 16.4 version of
postgress that is hardcoded and is the
gospel it doesn't matter what's it
doesn't matter that the value file is
totally screwed up and says in tag to
version 13 of postrest that is the
gospel therefore you can go forth and
Conquer knowing that that is the way
it's supposed to be so if you go back
though um you can you can look here now
at the the the resource file for the
values and and using Mac hell yeah I'm
using Mac why would I
not you couldn't hear you couldn't hear
I feel so bad let me let me do that
again for
you
here a unic
system Mac is a unic system it qualifies
Unix is way cooler than Linux so anyway
here we go um uh X resource values file
so here's the vales file there it is
okay so right away let me show you how
this differentiated from the the actual
uh original Harbor one right so um and I
think I actually have
that yes I do so let's uh let's dip
resources uh values
uh-
Harbor and resources values they're the
same essentially so these are the this
is the only thing that changed between
the two um so here we have a tag that's
13.6 okay and that's the broken tag
we've already talked about that in a
separate video so we updated to 16.4
which by the way it's consistent with
the dependency I just showed you in the
charts. loock
file right
so I'm not going to rant anymore about
that I want to um here we have backup
enable true where did I find that I
found that because I went to the post I
told you in a previous video I went into
the postgress uh bitnami chart and I saw
this thing called backup in there I saw
this PG dump step and I was like what's
that about because I'm about to write
all that it was already there the whole
time so I just had to turn that to true
the reason that's not there is because
it's not in the harbor yaml file the
harbor. Amo file why because Helm does
something very strange with dependent
sub charts and I'm going to end with
this but it's super important that you
understand this if you don't understand
anything else about Helm in this video
just know this when you do Helm show
values in order to generate the values
file that you're going to go in and then
update right and you have subchart
dependencies and you can look for those
in charts. loock or you can look them at
at the top of the chart file with the
dependencies I don't know why they're
both there with authoritative place to
look for them honest to God is here
because it actually has the version
locked down so go look in chart. loock
versus chart. yaml so this is more than
you ever want to know about home but
maybe this will save somebody else pain
and suffering so all these images and
infrastructures annotations these are
wrong this is completely wrong and this
here this list of dependencies is all
nice and everything but it doesn't lock
down the version it's like oh you can
lock that that version some place I
don't know this must be because it's
metadata or because it's documentation
data I don't know I don't care Because
the actual version is in chart. loock so
just know that the actual version for
this chart is in chart. loock this means
that effectively effectively when you
run Helm template or you run Helm
install either way what Helm is doing
and and this could be this we just
confirm this by looking at the resulting
manifest the yo files that come out of
those commands right so what Helm does
whether it's documented this way or not
is it it grabs these in starts with its
own yaml that you know values. yaml file
and it starts with its own stuff and it
runs its chart file and it uses those
value to generate all its stuff and then
it grabs the entire uh uh value default
values. yaml and the entire chart for
every one of its dependencies redus
postris and in this case common right
and those things
become logical logically included into
the chart so that means all the the
values. this is very important okay I'm
going to pause here for fact all of the
values. yaml from the postgress bami
chart dependency all of the values. yaml
from the reddish chart dependency are
effectively and logically included when
you run the template command even though
when you do the show show values you
know Helm show values command to get the
harbor values. yaml file you are not
getting the values files for reddis or
postgress but they are still valid and
and then to top it all off um in order
to make it easier for us they have
allowed us to put all of that into the
values file which is why you get crap
like this you get this thing right so
this is how Helm Works Helm says if
there is a you know farthest to the left
uh postgress dsql in in this case
that matches one of our Helm dependency
names everything in here is
authoritative everything in here wins
over the other Upstream chart values. yo
file that's kind of implicitly loaded
but not printed anywhere now the thing
that bothers the crap out of me is that
when you do show values here there is no
option let me this is very important I
looked for it forever and if you know
where it is please put it in the
comments I'll come kiss you on the mouth
there is no option to do Helm show
values that will that will pull down the
values. yaml files for each of these
subchart dependencies in an organized
way so that you have them all along with
your values. yl file from the the the
core repo that you're copying this means
that if you want to follow the flatten
and then apply kind of idea that most of
us do that's the idea behind my Kap and
our specification for kaps if you want
to do this properly then the only way to
do it is to do show values and save up
resources values. yaml but in addition
to that you have to call that same exact
command for every of the one of the sub
charts and then and then this is where
they Comes This is where the kicker
comes in in order to include those all
right so you have them all for reference
and in order to include those all and to
get them all into the final template you
have to
modify your build command which I have
not yet done but you have to modify your
build command to include all of those
resources so values Dart values d
postgress uh reddis Etc you can either
do that or you can just look at those
charts and do what I did with the backup
and then go into the master values. yo
file and override them at that location
so that you don't have to keep that but
most people most people who are going to
want to flatten they're going to want to
keep a hold of those charts because
they're going to want to know what
changed between versions and there's no
way to know that if you have a
dependency like let's say let's say the
subchart dependency were to change right
and you would have no way to know how
the value file change from what you just
built to the new one you have no way of
knowing that because you can't dip the
previous values in the file not to
mention the fact that all the comments
that come in the value spile that we've
gotten used to reading and knowing oh
I'm going to go change this thing here
don't exist they don't exist because
they are not in the subchart they're not
they're they're not stored anywhere so
you have to go get them by yourself
that's the only way to do it now there
is one remaining mystery and that is
what
wins right I have a feeling that the the
the main values file for the main
project in this case Harbor wins out
over everything else but I'm going to
further do some research here to find
out if the order of the file inclusions
which I which was totally it said
multiple files allowed and I was like oh
okay so I I didn't know that before and
so what this means is that it's very
possible that the last file wins right
so any place that you have Global values
that that conflict with one another and
and I'm I'm pretty positive there's
going to be some pretty radical Helm
scope uh naming collisions that are
going to happen and so I'm going to
proceed to test what happens when you
download the entire postest values file
and combine it in this way rather than
just overriding it as a tiny little
section within the supported you know
and included postgress uh part of the
harbor yaml file um I I personally I
don't I I would rather not do that right
I I would rather have the entire values
files for each of the subchart
dependencies available so I know what
I'm dealing with and hopefully this has
helped you understand home a little bit
more I had to make this video because
it's driving me absolutely crazy and
it's the weekend and I want to get out
of here hope you had fun figuring this
out as well as I did bye